[{"question": "Asks about how parents, specifically moms, have supported individuals during their IVF journey.", "answer": "Responses vary, with some parents providing emotional support, financial assistance, and practical help like cooking meals or attending appointments. However, some individuals have experienced insensitivity, pressure, or lack of understanding from their parents during their IVF journey. Setting boundaries and seeking support from friends, coworkers, or other family members are suggested for those facing unsupportive reactions from parents.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1ai59th/supportive_parents/", "score": 44}, {"question": "Addresses the backlash faced by individuals advocating for more access to fertility treatments, specifically IVF, with comments suggesting that those who can't conceive naturally don't deserve to be parents.", "answer": "Comments express frustration and disbelief at the lack of empathy and understanding from critics of IVF. They highlight the hypocrisy of those who oppose IVF, pointing out that many individuals may change their stance if faced with infertility themselves. The comments emphasize the importance of ignoring such negative opinions and focusing on individual paths to parenthood, while also highlighting the medical necessity and complexity of infertility treatments like IVF.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b2ssfi/apparently_if_you_cant_conceive_naturally_you/", "score": 194}, {"question": "Inquires about the experience of transferring as a single parent following the unexpected passing of a spouse.", "answer": "Commenters express condolences and advise taking time to grieve, seek therapy, and carefully consider the decision of single parenthood. They highlight the challenges of pregnancy, raising a child alone, and emphasize the importance of having a strong support system and financial stability.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17vbhl4/transferring_as_a_single_parent/", "score": 57}, {"question": "Asks for experiences and opinions on transferring one or two embryos, specifically in the context of wanting one of each sex and potential downsides like difficulty and potential loss.", "answer": "A user shared their experience of transferring two embryos after a failed FET and ending up pregnant with boy/girl twins. They expressed a mix of excitement and fear as first-time parents.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/zqz4rc/double_transfer_twin_parent_regrets/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks if anyone has experienced a failed Frozen Embryo Transfer (FET) after multiple successful pregnancies through IVF.", "answer": "Comments indicate that not every transfer is successful, even after multiple successful pregnancies. It is acknowledged as part of the process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1bmt4ph/tw_question_for_parents_of_multiple_ivf_babies/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Asks how to manage working with new parents and newborns as a postpartum doula while dealing with personal fertility challenges.", "answer": "Comments suggest that the emotional toll of working in a field related to newborns and fertility can be challenging, especially after experiencing negative treatment outcomes. Some individuals are exploring other career options for their mental well-being, while others find solace in the shared experiences of infertility within their work environment. Ultimately, finding peace with whatever decision is made is important.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18pbywv/working_with_new_parentsnewborns/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks if parents are legally required to disclose if the individual is a donor child.", "answer": "In most cases, parents are not legally obligated to disclose this information. Ancestry or 23andMe tests can help uncover biological connections. Joining support communities like r/donorconceived can offer assistance and guidance in such situations.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b4bjv2/are_my_parents_legally_required_to_tell_me_if_ima/", "score": 7}, {"question": "Asks why the clinic is requiring the non-biological parent in a same-sex couple to undergo bloodwork and a semen analysis for IVF using donor eggs and sperm.", "answer": "Commenters suggest that the clinic's requirement may be unnecessary and potentially a way to charge for services not needed. They recommend seeking clarification from the doctor to understand the reasoning behind the request.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/ucs8mh/question_about_semen_analysis_requirement_for/", "score": 11}, {"question": "Expresses concern about the low number of fertilized eggs and worries about being bad parents for already counting out potential children.", "answer": "Assures that feeling this way does not make one a bad parent, as it is based on statistics and science. Mentions that only about 40% of fertilized eggs are expected to make it to the blastocyst stage, and then only about 50% of those may be normal. Shares personal experience with similar low numbers of fertilized eggs, highlighting the unpredictability of the IVF process. Encourages positive thinking and sends well wishes for success in the IVF journey.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/13s5jib/are_we_bad_parents_already/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Asks if both parents need to have fertility coverage/insurance for IVF to be covered.", "answer": "Only the individual undergoing the procedures needs to be on a plan with fertility coverage. The partner's coverage is not necessary unless they are undergoing their own procedures or testing.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/179ytnt/do_both_parents_need_fertility_coverage_insurance/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for online forums or group chats for lesbians undergoing IVF, specifically for the non-carrying partner, to discuss emotions and experiences related to pregnancy.", "answer": "One comment suggests checking out the subreddit r/queerception as a potential online community for support and information on this topic.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/13bjbkh/lesbian_parents_ivf/", "score": 8}, {"question": "Questions the lack of emotional support from parents/in-laws regarding fertility struggles and IVF process.", "answer": "People may not understand the emotional toll of fertility treatments and assume IVF always leads to pregnancy. Some may dismiss the struggles or invalidate feelings due to cultural beliefs or lack of personal experience.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16emt4a/disappointed_by_the_lack_of_support_from_parents/", "score": 12}, {"question": "Asks about the importance of feeling an immediate connection with a surrogate during the matching process.", "answer": "Some individuals prioritize assessing the surrogate's responsibility, reliability, and authenticity over establishing a personal connection. The significance of a connection may vary depending on personal preferences and circumstances.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/139pre4/intended_parents_meet_surrogate/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Inquires about the cost of parent genetic screening in the USA.", "answer": "The cost can vary depending on the company used by the clinic. Prices mentioned in the comments range from $349 to $8,000, with insurance coverage playing a significant role in covering the expenses.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/pkxkpv/how_much_does_parent_genetic_screening_cost_usa/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Seeks advice on dealing with parental pressure and negative comments during the IVF journey.", "answer": "Recommendations include setting boundaries with family members, limiting the number of people aware of the IVF journey, and directly addressing the unhelpful and damaging comments by expressing that such remarks are not welcome.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/rb037u/parental_pressure_sucks/", "score": 11}, {"question": "Asks if it is normal for husbands or partners to freak out about becoming parents during the IVF process.", "answer": "It is not uncommon for partners to have doubts and fears during the IVF journey. Some may experience panic and uncertainty, but with time and space to work through their emotions, they often come around and embrace the idea of parenthood. Communication and being gentle with each other are crucial during this emotional rollercoaster.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/o0vrl5/husbands_or_partners_freaking_out_about_becoming/", "score": 6}, {"question": "Inquires about the necessity of having samples from parents for PGD IVF procedure with Natera.", "answer": "Natera may require samples from parents if both partners are found to be carriers for the same disorder to create a specific probe for checking embryos. Contacting Natera for guidance on the process and answering questions is recommended.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/172hvan/natera_asking_samples_from_my_parents_for_our_pgd/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks whether to disclose the use of an egg donor to parents, considering their overbearing nature and potential negative reaction.", "answer": "Comment suggests that disclosure should be based on what is best for the child, prioritizing their understanding of their genetic story. Parents' feelings should not factor in, and openness from the outset is generally recommended for the child's benefit.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/11pw9h9/disclose_egg_donation_to_my_parents/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Asks for feedback on creating a database to anonymously share medical data about donor-conceived children with their half-siblings.", "answer": "The post does not have any comments or responses to the survey request.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1608w0x/market_survey_for_connecting_recipient_parents/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for others' experiences with choosing to undergo IVF as a single parent using donor sperm embryos.", "answer": "A commenter shared their story of undergoing IVF on their own, emphasizing the benefits of going with donor sperm embryos and the importance of considering the limited window for fertility success compared to the lifetime potential to meet a partner.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/jsgdsl/38f_and_single_parent_may_be_my_only_option/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks if anyone else is a step-parent going through the IVF journey and experiencing complex emotions about parenting their stepchild.", "answer": "Comments reassure that such feelings are natural for step-parents in similar situations. It is praised that the individual is self-aware and seeking advice. Recommendations for parenting books are shared to help navigate the situation. Overall, support and understanding are conveyed towards the individual.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/mjsrdl/is_anyone_else_doing_this_journey_as_well_as/", "score": 17}, {"question": "Asks for advice on how to deal with parents-in-law constantly asking for 'good news' about pregnancy, especially when undergoing IVF treatments.", "answer": "Suggestions include having the husband address the issue with his parents and setting clear boundaries. Responding with humor or assertiveness can also help handle such intrusive questions.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/x4yic6/what_to_say_to_parentsinlaws_who_keep_asking_for/", "score": 33}, {"question": "Asks for advice on explaining the IVF process to in-laws who may not fully understand the challenges of battling infertility.", "answer": "Some suggestions include setting boundaries on sharing details, being selective about who to share the journey with, providing educational resources such as podcasts, and seeking support from those who are empathetic and understanding. It's important to prioritize self-care and choose to disclose information only to supportive individuals.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/117sjgg/advice_needed_how_did_you_explain_the_fertility/", "score": 18}, {"question": "Asks if PGT-M testing is necessary for embryos if only one parent is a carrier of a recessive disease.", "answer": "Comments suggest that PGT-M testing is not necessary if only one parent is a carrier, as both parents need to be carriers for the gene to manifest in the child.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/143nyzc/do_both_parents_need_to_be_a_genetic_carrier_to/", "score": 6}, {"question": "Asks how to manage support from parents during IVF, especially when they may say triggering things despite good intentions.", "answer": "Some individuals choose not to disclose IVF plans to avoid potentially triggering comments. Educating parents through resources like blogs can help them understand better. Open communication with parents about what kind of support is needed is crucial.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/kbtdft/managing_your_parents_through_ivf/", "score": 7}, {"question": "Asks if anyone else has gone through genetic testing during IVF and discovered unexpected findings about themselves or their partners.", "answer": "Some individuals have discovered inherited genetic traits or conditions about themselves or their partners through genetic testing during IVF. Pre-IVF genetic counseling can help uncover such information, which may not always be openly discussed by doctors due to the complexity and rarity of certain genetic findings.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/vdl5dz/when_genetic_testing_reveals_more_about_the/", "score": 7}, {"question": "Asks for advice on how to find their biological egg donor or potential half-siblings.", "answer": "Comment suggests starting with DNA kits like 23andMe to connect with relatives and potentially find the egg donor or half-siblings.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/vgbm78/looking_for_my_parents_egg_donor/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks why individuals are undergoing IVF/fertility treatment, with various reasons such as genetic concerns, medical conditions, male factor infertility, advanced maternal age, unexplained infertility, PCOS, and prior health issues like chemo or scar tissue affecting fertility.", "answer": "The reasons for IVF treatment range from genetic conditions and male factor infertility to advanced maternal age, unexplained infertility, PCOS, and previous health issues impacting fertility. Some individuals are using IVF for gender selection, surrogacy, and addressing chromosomal abnormalities.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b44vel/why_are_you_personally_having_ivffertility/", "score": 5}, {"question": "Seeks advice and support regarding IVF journey with donor eggs, multiple failed transfers, and current pregnancy with a hematoma.", "answer": "High HCG levels are generally positive indicators for a successful pregnancy. Hematomas can be managed with bed rest and have been experienced in successful pregnancies. Encouragement and well wishes for a healthy pregnancy are shared.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/pknuag/cautiously_optimistic_older_parents_donor_eggs/", "score": 35}, {"question": "Asks how family members (parents, in-laws, siblings) react to the IVF journey.", "answer": "Responses vary from lack of understanding or insensitivity to strong support. Some family members may hold religious beliefs that go against IVF, while others may have personal reactions based on biological ties. Communication and boundaries play a significant role in managing family dynamics during the IVF process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/uhxfrt/how_does_your_family_parents_siblings_inlaws/", "score": 7}, {"question": "Asks for advice on options for pregnancy when both parents are carriers of Congenital Adrenal Hyperplasia (CAH).", "answer": "One option suggested is Preimplantation Genetic Testing for Monogenic Disorders (PGT-M) to test embryos for the specific mutation related to CAH. This can help in achieving a healthy pregnancy and is commonly done for genetic disorders like CAH. It is recommended to consult with the IVF clinic and the lab they use for PGT to inquire about testing for CAH.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/k9d7gv/are_there_any_parents_in_here_that_are_carriers/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Expresses frustration with insensitive comments from friends and family trying to empathize with their infertility struggles by comparing it to their own difficulties in conceiving.", "answer": "Comments suggest that such comparisons can be hurtful and highlight the importance of finding a therapist who truly understands infertility and can provide genuine support. Recommendations for therapists who specialize in IVF and have personal experience with infertility are given as potential options for better understanding and empathy.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/w8ps7s/parents_trying_to_empathise_when_i_know_my/", "score": 14}, {"question": "Asks for advice on dealing with toxic family dynamics, specifically regarding infertility and IVF, and the potential repercussions of cutting off contact with family members.", "answer": "Commenters suggest considering cutting off communication with toxic family members, prioritizing one's own well-being and mental health. They emphasize surrounding oneself with loving and supportive individuals, even if they are not blood-related.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/wuzx2n/ivf_is_hard_and_my_parents_are_the_worst_people/", "score": 8}, {"question": "Expresses feeling lonely and hesitant to share about their IVF journey with others besides their parents.", "answer": "Sharing with others can lead to discovering shared experiences and support, as many people are going through or have been through IVF. However, some choose to keep their journey private due to personal reasons or to avoid unnecessary stress from others.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/q5jb1n/lonely_journey_im_not_telling_anyone_about_ivf/", "score": 10}, {"question": "Asks for advice on whether to proceed with a transfer of the last frozen embryo or to do a stim/egg retrieval given the age factor and success rates.", "answer": "Comments suggest trying with the remaining embryos first and then considering egg retrieval based on AMH, AFC, and FSH levels. Also, reassures the poster about their age and the benefits of being more mature and calmer during the process, especially with a child wanting a sibling.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/soyxtk/inviting_advice_and_perspective_to_help_us_become/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Expresses shock and frustration over encountering ignorant views on IVF, questioning the morality of the procedure and likening it to unnatural acts.", "answer": "Comments reflect anger towards individuals condemning IVF, highlighting the necessity of medical interventions like IVF and comparing it to other accepted medical procedures. They emphasize the importance of standing up against ignorance and judgment towards those undergoing IVF, and the need to distance oneself from platforms like TikTok where such views are perpetuated.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/194r3ge/tiktok_just_showed_me_a_video_about_how_ivf_is/", "score": 159}, {"question": "Expresses frustration and despair over the challenges of IVF, feeling isolated and misunderstood in their journey towards motherhood.", "answer": "Comments offer empathy and understanding, acknowledging the emotional, physical, and financial toll of IVF. Members share their own struggles, feelings of being misunderstood, and eventual success stories to provide hope and solidarity to the original poster. The community is seen as a source of comfort and support during this difficult journey.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16sotqi/drained/", "score": 203}, {"question": "Expresses confusion and mixed emotions about starting IVF after years of infertility struggles, questioning if feelings of nervousness about becoming a parent are a defense mechanism.", "answer": "Other individuals going through similar struggles share the sentiment of feeling conflicted about parenthood after years of fertility treatments. They suggest that these feelings may indeed be a defense mechanism to protect oneself from potential disappointment. It's important to acknowledge and address these emotions and be kind to oneself throughout the process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/wwxj09/struggling_with_trying_to_understand_why_im/", "score": 24}, {"question": "Asks individuals the reason for undergoing IVF/fertility treatment, such as medical problems, same-sex relationship, or being a single parent.", "answer": "Reasons include solo motherhood by choice with genetic screening, using donor sperm due to azoospermia, unexplained infertility with multiple miscarriages, and IVF being the only option due to CBAVD in the male partner.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b44vbt/why_are_you_personally_having_ivffertility/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Asks if anyone else is experiencing conflicting feelings about wanting to become a mother while going through IVF.", "answer": "Several commenters share their experiences of being uncertain about motherhood before IVF but finding clarity during the process. Therapy is mentioned as a helpful tool in navigating these conflicting emotions. Some individuals found that going through IVF helped them make a decision, whether it worked or not, and set boundaries on the number of procedures they were willing to undergo.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/13isqpy/ivf_when_you_feel_unsure_you_want_kids/", "score": 88}, {"question": "Asks if IVF can be requested solely due to a strong sex preference in the US and if insurance would cover it under this circumstance.", "answer": "It is possible to request IVF for a strong sex preference, but insurance may not cover elective procedures. Speaking to a therapist before trying to conceive is strongly recommended due to concerns about toxic gender norms and the pressure such preferences may place on a child.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/efw1wz/thoughtsexperiences_on_ivf_for_healthy_parents/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Asks about the number of transfer attempts it took to get pregnant and at what age others started the IVF process, got pregnant, and had a baby.", "answer": "Success varies; some get pregnant after the first transfer, while others may take multiple attempts. Examples include successful pregnancies at ages 37, 38, 44, and 47, with varying numbers of IVF rounds and embryos transferred.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1bce6xn/transfers/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Post shares about going for a second egg retrieval in IVF journey, expressing gratitude and hope for the process.", "answer": "Comments offer words of encouragement, support, and good wishes for successful results and a smooth recovery.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1as9s10/2nd_retrieval_this_morning/", "score": 19}, {"question": "Expresses fears and doubts about pursuing IVF, including concerns about being a parent, postpartum depression, financial investment, and whether it's the right choice to make.", "answer": "Comments share personal experiences of initial doubts and fears before undergoing IVF, highlighting the emotional and financial challenges of the process. Some express moments of panic, questioning if they will be good parents, and feeling overwhelmed by the uncertainties and sacrifices involved. Others reflect on the desire for a family and the long-term fulfillment it may bring, despite the challenges. Ultimately, the decision to pursue IVF or not should align with personal desires and values, ensuring that one is fully comfortable with their choice.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/t8xz2p/feelings_of_is_this_even_what_i_want/", "score": 94}, {"question": "Asks whether it is necessary to share the IVF journey with others.", "answer": "Responses vary, with some individuals choosing to share their IVF journey with everyone, including family, friends, and even strangers, while others prefer to keep it private due to concerns about comparisons, stigma, or unwanted opinions. It is emphasized that the decision to share or not share should be based on individual comfort levels and support systems.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1ayp6bb/do_you_tell_everyone_youre_going_through_ivf/", "score": 44}, {"question": "Expresses distress over a failed IVF transfer and financial constraints preventing further attempts.", "answer": "Offers sympathy and encouragement for the remaining day 7 embryo, understanding the emotional and financial difficulties associated with IVF struggles.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18dvmpq/im_a_mess/", "score": 34}, {"question": "Asks for advice on which embryo to transfer first, given a preference for a girl but concern about limited female embryos in case of initial failure.", "answer": "Commenters suggest various approaches, including letting the embryologist select the highest graded embryo, prioritizing the best graded one regardless of sex, and some sharing personal experiences of choosing based on preference or simply opting for the best graded embryo.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/120j0n6/what_embryo_to_transfer_first/", "score": 6}, {"question": "Expresses feelings of hopelessness and exhaustion in the IVF journey, questioning the purpose and outcome of the process.", "answer": "Comments offer empathy and support, acknowledging the emotional toll of IVF and the importance of seeking help, such as therapy, to cope with the challenges. It is highlighted that taking a break and prioritizing self-care is crucial in navigating the emotional rollercoaster of IVF.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18njh6g/i_actually_dont_think_i_can_keep_doing_this/", "score": 41}, {"question": "Asks for advice on sharing information about IVF outside of the relationship, specifically with family members.", "answer": "Comments suggest that sharing IVF experiences with family and friends is a personal choice. Some find support and understanding, while others regret sharing due to insensitivity or unwanted advice. It is recommended to assess the need for support and the dynamics of relationships before deciding to share such personal information.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16zs2ui/when_did_you_start_telling_people/", "score": 20}, {"question": "Asks about the chances of having unaffected embryos during IVF when both partners have NF1 genetic condition.", "answer": "It is suggested that with both parents having NF1, there is a 25% chance of having unaffected embryos during IVF. Consulting a genetic counselor or a doctor specializing in NF1 is recommended for specific guidance and advice on the genetic inheritance pattern and potential outcomes.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18v2atw/ivf_genetics_question/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks for positive/happy stories to help cope with anxiety during the waiting period post-embryo transfer.", "answer": "Suggestion to have the clinic call the partner with the results instead of the patient, allowing for a better time and place to receive potentially emotional news.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1au9zz8/6dp5dt_and_going_insane/", "score": 10}, {"question": "Asks for suggestions on the next steps in the IVF process after experiencing recurrent miscarriages due to genetic abnormalities in embryos.", "answer": "Recommendations include considering a full Recurrent Pregnancy Loss (RPL) panel testing for the wife, including autoimmune testing and hysteroscopy. Additional testing can help identify potential underlying issues such as endometritis or inflammation that could be treated for better success in future IVF cycles.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1am52f2/in_need_of_suggestions_for_next_steps/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Asks about the possibility of single women undergoing IVF without the need for a spouse or guardian to be involved in the process.", "answer": "Some clinics may require a witness for certain procedures, but it can be anyone other than a spouse. Single women have successfully undergone IVF with donor sperm in various locations, including conservative states like Missouri and countries like Australia and Mexico. Being single during IVF treatment is seen as a better option compared to being in a bad or abusive relationship.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/141bdc8/any_single_women_doing_ivf/", "score": 33}, {"question": "Asks if it is possible to find bio parents as a child born through IVF and expresses concerns about genetic predisposition to mental illness.", "answer": "Clarification is given that IVF can involve using one's own eggs and sperm, and it's not explicitly stated in the post if donor material was used. There is support for exploring the possibility of finding bio parents and understanding genetic predispositions, with reassurance that it's okay to have these feelings while still valuing the relationships with current family members.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/mec49e/not_sure_if_these_kind_of_posts_are_allowed_here/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Expresses emotional distress and feelings of hopelessness after experiencing a failed IVF attempt as a single parent.", "answer": "Another single parent empathizes, sharing their own struggles and determination to keep trying despite setbacks. They understand the loss of time, money, effort, hope, and joy but emphasize not giving up on the dream of parenthood.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18ym6uy/need_a_hug_please/", "score": 10}, {"question": "Expresses the emotional pain and disappointment of a long infertility journey that has not resulted in a successful pregnancy, leading to the decision to end further treatments.", "answer": "Encouragement to take time to grieve and heal, support from the community, suggestions for self-care and alternative paths to parenthood such as considering egg donation or exploring childfree options.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b0yr2x/our_journey_is_coming_to_an_end/", "score": 375}, {"question": "Expresses frustration and grief over undergoing IVF treatment while dealing with the sudden loss of a parent.", "answer": "Comments offer condolences and support for the individual during this challenging time, acknowledging the insensitivity of others and sending wishes for healing and peace.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17ym240/life_is_unfair/", "score": 93}, {"question": "Asks who to share IVF journey with - family, friends, employer, etc.?", "answer": "It varies - some share with close family and friends for support, while others prefer to keep it private to avoid unwanted questions or stress. Consider sharing with those who can offer understanding and respect boundaries. Some choose to share selectively based on comfort level and preference for support.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1afm5qa/to_tell_or_not_to_tell/", "score": 11}, {"question": "Expresses frustration at lack of emotional support and acknowledgment from family during IVF process, particularly after significant procedures like egg retrieval.", "answer": "Family members may avoid discussing IVF due to discomfort, lack of understanding, or fear of overstepping boundaries. Some may prefer to wait for pregnancy news rather than delve into details of the process. It may be helpful to communicate feelings with family members to set expectations and seek the support needed.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1as67o8/family_havent_bothered_checking_in/", "score": 30}, {"question": "Asks for advice on the ideal age to try for a baby as a single woman freezing eggs at 38, considering the challenges of dating and parenthood desires.", "answer": "One commenter suggests not waiting until 42, sharing her experience of fertility struggles despite starting at 32. Recommends prioritizing having a baby over waiting for a partner, suggesting making embryos if that's the primary goal.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1aecm2z/what_would_you_do/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks about the experience of undergoing an egg retrieval procedure during IVF.", "answer": "The process is described as manageable and less daunting than anticipated. Patients are sedated for the procedure, which is generally quick and pain is managed with medication. Recovery involves taking it easy for a few days, with some experiencing mild cramping afterwards.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/19c761f/first_er_bit_scared/", "score": 15}, {"question": "Inquires about the probability of a child being Autosomal Recessive when one parent is autosomal recessive and the other parent does not carry any disease versions of the gene.", "answer": "Comments suggest that the child has a 50% chance of being an unaffected carrier like the parent, with a near 0% chance of being affected by the disease. There is a rare possibility of inheriting an undetected disease variant from the other parent.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16nxoo7/autosomal_recessive_gene_question/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks what to do with embryos created with a cheating husband's DNA, considering the legal and emotional complexities involved.", "answer": "Comments suggest options such as leaving the embryos banked, discussing with the husband to sign over rights, using the embryos and potentially dealing with legal implications, or creating new embryos with donor sperm to avoid potential custody battles and legal drama.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/u9lmnv/day_4_cheating_husband_discovered/", "score": 33}, {"question": "Seeking support and virtual hugs after a hurtful confrontation with their mother regarding IVF and parenting.", "answer": "Encouragement to not let external judgments affect their self-worth. Suggestion to seek therapy to work through the emotional impact of the situation.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1bic4o9/virtual_hugs_please/", "score": 7}, {"question": "Asks if others experience sadness and frustration over not having the life they envisioned due to infertility treatments.", "answer": "Comments express feelings of mourning the life they don't have and the life they had before infertility treatments. The emotional toll and uncertainty of fertility treatments are highlighted, with some finding solace in small getaways like trips to Paris or Mexico.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/198wheb/mourning_the_life_you_dont_have/", "score": 174}, {"question": "No specific question asked in the post, just a recommendation for a funny IVF-related podcast episode.", "answer": "Commenter expresses gratitude for the podcast recommendation and mentions an interest in listening to new podcast episodes related to IVF experiences.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/169i72u/really_funny_ivf_podcast_40/", "score": 13}, {"question": "Asks why infertility seems more prevalent in newer generations compared to older ones.", "answer": "Possible reasons suggested by comments include delayed childbearing, environmental factors such as plastics and chemicals, lifestyle choices like diet and pollution, and increased awareness and openness about infertility leading to more diagnoses. Additionally, advancements in fertility treatments like IVF and IUI have made conception possible for individuals who may have struggled with infertility in the past.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/16s89zh/what_is_it_that_causing_infertility_in_our/", "score": 29}, {"question": "Asks for podcasts and videos on IVF from the child's perspective, not just detailed medical journeys of parents.", "answer": "Comments suggest exploring resources on how to explain IVF conception to children.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/12ntw98/podcasts_and_videos_on_things_like_ivf_about_or/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks about the purpose of blood tests (thyroid, full blood count, vitamin D) required before starting IVF.", "answer": "The tests are standard before IVF and help assess factors like thyroid function, anemia, vitamin D levels, and impact on things like embryo transfer and AMH levels.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17qyb5k/what_are_these_blood_tests_for_anyone_know/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks about the doctor's reaction to a low hcg level of 46 and if it was appropriate or gaslighting.", "answer": "Commenters empathize with the OP's experience and express outrage at the doctor's response, noting that a beta of 46 is concerning and should warrant careful monitoring. They share their own experiences of low betas that turned out positively, emphasizing that outcomes can vary and offer support during the stressful time.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/188igdl/low_betarude_doctor/", "score": 16}, {"question": "Asks how to obtain family medical history as a double donor-conceived individual to help with ongoing health issues.", "answer": "Suggestions include taking a DNA test, seeking support from communities like r/donorconceived, and using resources like PimEyes to potentially find donor information through adult photos.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18nzywa/im_an_ivf_twin_both_of_us_have_health_issues_and/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Expresses frustration and unfairness over the financial burden of IVF treatment compared to relatives who may not prioritize their health or unborn child's well-being.", "answer": "Comments provide empathy and support, acknowledging the emotional toll of infertility and the unfairness of the situation. Encouragement is given to acknowledge and express these feelings while also finding ways to cope and continue moving forward in the journey.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/w9l642/there_is_nothing_more_unfair_than_infertility/", "score": 140}, {"question": "Asks about the extent of gene selection in IVF, including selecting gender, having twins or triplets, and choosing traits like height.", "answer": "", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b4tyf1/how_much_of_traits_can_i_select_in_an_ivf/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Expresses frustration over being referred to IVF babies as \"test tube babies\" and worries about potential discrimination from family members based on the conception method.", "answer": "Comments provide various responses and coping mechanisms, including using humor to deflect comments, confronting individuals who use derogatory terms, and highlighting the importance of standing up for oneself and one's future children regardless of how they were conceived. Some also share personal experiences of facing judgment or misunderstanding surrounding IVF conception.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1arj8a9/does_it_bother_anyone_else_when_others_refer_to/", "score": 79}, {"question": "Expresses frustration over a spouse not using organic beef in a meal, despite undergoing extensive measures during IVF treatments to optimize chances of success.", "answer": "Some commenters suggest that the focus on organic beef may be excessive and not necessarily supported by science. Others empathize with the feeling of being responsible for every detail during fertility treatments and understand the frustration of not having preferences considered.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b6hykc/husband_made_burgers_with_conventional_beef/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Inquires about the relative costs (emotional, timewise, and financial) of pursuing IVF versus adoption/fostering in building a family.", "answer": "Prioritizing procreation that preserves genetics versus other methods is a personal decision. Some individuals consider fostering but may not pursue it due to time constraints and the intensive nature of the process, which includes numerous appointments and commitments.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1b6s5su/seeking_info_regarding_ivf_versus/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Asks for suggestions, tips, and advice for starting the IVF journey.", "answer": "Brace yourself for potential challenges and remember that the process can be emotionally taxing. Take it day by day and lean on support systems. Consider discussing couples counseling with your spouse to prioritize your relationship throughout the IVF journey.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/xlejqa/its_starting_to_feel_real/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks for advice or shared experiences from others who have undergone IVF and felt a mix of excitement and fear.", "answer": "Commenters empathize with the fear of IVF not working and the emotional impact it can have. They offer support and encouragement, acknowledging the courage and strength needed for the IVF journey.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/14jthss/my_one_chance_starts_july_17th/", "score": 2}, {"question": "Expresses deep frustration and sadness due to infertility struggles while witnessing others easily conceive and parent, despite facing challenges in caring for their children.", "answer": "Comments empathize with the OP's feelings of jealousy and unfairness, sharing similar experiences of struggling with infertility while observing others effortlessly conceive. Some discuss the impact of endometriosis on fertility and the lack of awareness around it. There is also a sense of frustration towards societal expectations around fertility, highlighting the perceived ease with which some individuals conceive despite their lifestyle choices.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1aj1m1t/fuck_infertility/", "score": 160}, {"question": "Asks how to deal with feeling distance from friends who have had successful pregnancies while going through IVF struggles and multiple losses.", "answer": "Comments suggest giving oneself time and space to heal, surrounding oneself with understanding people, evaluating events based on personal feelings, and prioritizing mental health. It's important to communicate with friends when ready and give and receive grace during difficult times.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/188by91/friend_issues/", "score": 24}, {"question": "Asks if the IVF process can trigger mental changes similar to those experienced during pregnancy and childbirth.", "answer": "One commenter with brain injury/trauma from excision did not experience ill effects during 2 rounds of IVF, with approval from neuro-oncologist and neurologist. They are open to discussing more via DM.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/zmc0yd/mental_changes_during_or_after_ivf/", "score": 4}, {"question": "Asks for advice and insight from mothers over 40 regarding concerns about age and IVF success.", "answer": "Comments provide reassurance and personal anecdotes from older mothers who successfully had children through IVF in their 40s, highlighting the rewards and joys of late motherhood. They emphasize that age is just a number and that what matters most is what feels right for the individual. Various individuals share their experiences of having successful pregnancies and becoming mothers in their 40s, showcasing that it is possible and can bring immense joy and fulfillment.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18rozj1/after_4_egg_retrievals_this_year_my_mom_politely/", "score": 48}, {"question": "Expresses frustration with in-laws expecting normal behavior during IVF process and not understanding the emotional trauma involved.", "answer": "Some commenters relate to similar situations with in-laws wanting constant updates and involvement during IVF, despite expressing a desire for privacy. Suggests setting boundaries with in-laws and prioritizing emotional well-being during the process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1653zhf/unreasonable_inlaws/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Asks if anyone has drafted a legal document specifying who can receive their frozen embryos in the event of both partners passing away before implantation.", "answer": "Some clinics provide forms detailing the fate of embryos in case of the patient's passing before transfer, which may include instructions on who can receive legal custody.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/15h5cl1/legal_document_for_embryos/", "score": 0}, {"question": "Asks if Natera requires parents' DNA for PGT-M testing and when they inform patients about this requirement.", "answer": "Natera may require parents' DNA for PGT-M testing, with the process involving sending separate samples for gene screening and DNA analysis. Patients may need to plan for delays in processing and should be prepared for a slow process with Natera.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1bi6gxe/natera_pgtm/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Expresses doubts and fears about becoming a parent, feeling disinterested in other people's children, and questioning their readiness for the responsibilities of parenthood.", "answer": "Comments offer reassurance that it's normal to have conflicting feelings about parenthood, find other children annoying, and be unsure about the challenges ahead. Some share personal experiences of initially feeling disinterested in children but finding fulfillment in raising their own. They emphasize that parenthood is exhausting but rewarding, with love for one's own child being different from feelings towards others' children. It's noted that the journey of parenthood evolves as children grow and become more independent.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1benbk8/how_do_you_feel_about_babies_and_children_right/", "score": 97}, {"question": "Asks if IVF clinic can biopsy embryos and freeze them while awaiting PGT-M results, rather than waiting for the results before starting IVF.", "answer": "The clinic may not proceed with IVF until PGT-M results are available, as there is a risk that the probe may not be completed. The probe typically takes about 6 weeks, which is why the clinic prefers to wait before starting the IVF cycle process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/17fu5n9/pgtm_question/", "score": 3}, {"question": "Asks if anyone has used Orchid whole genome screening for embryos and what the data in the report includes, and if they would recommend it.", "answer": "A user shares a personal experience where a rare genetic disorder in their first daughter was only detected post-birth through whole genome sequencing. They express interest in Orchid's screening for potential benefits in detecting such disorders earlier in the IVF process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/18bnuns/have_you_used_orchid_whole_genome_screening_for/", "score": 5}, {"question": "Asks how going through infertility/IVF has changed outlook on pregnancy/parenting and life in general.", "answer": "", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/13qkmmy/reflection/", "score": 26}, {"question": "Asks about screening for cystic fibrosis carrier embryos when only one parent is a carrier, seeking recommendations.", "answer": "Based on personal experience, genetic counselors and physicians may not recommend screening for carrier embryos in such cases. It was advised to focus on PGT-M for a different condition instead.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/150fujj/cystic_fibrosis_carrier_embryo_genetic_screening/", "score": 1}, {"question": "Expresses devastation at receiving only 1 viable embryo out of 12 eggs during IVF process, seeking thoughts and inspiration.", "answer": "Commenters offer support and share similar experiences of low embryo yield, emphasizing the importance of remaining positive, sharing personal success stories, and advising on potential factors to improve outcomes, such as sperm health and lifestyle changes. It is highlighted that even one viable embryo can lead to a successful pregnancy, and that the IVF journey can be unpredictable but ultimately rewarding.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1afpg4r/were_devastated_there_is_still_hope_but_this_is/", "score": 89}, {"question": "Asks for advice on dealing with unsupportive parents regarding IVF journey.", "answer": "Some commenters suggest considering cutting ties with toxic family members, setting boundaries to protect oneself and future children, seeking therapy for emotional support, and being cautious about sharing IVF journey details with unsupportive individuals.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/qfe7d0/harsh_response/", "score": 13}, {"question": "No specific question is being asked in the post.", "answer": "Comments provide support, encouragement, and suggestions for staying relaxed and hydrated post FET. Recommendations include staying off feet, pampering oneself, watching movies, drinking lots of water, and seeking other food options besides water and McDonald's fries.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1av4eum/fet_this_morning/", "score": 69}, {"question": "Inquires about the appropriateness of asking if a pregnancy resulted from IVF or natural conception and seeks advice on handling such inquiries, especially from in-laws.", "answer": "Responses vary, with some finding the question intrusive and unnecessary, while others are open about their IVF journey and use it as an opportunity to educate others. Suggestions include proactively sharing the information to take control of the narrative and advocate for openness about fertility struggles.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1546tue/when_people_ask_if_your_pregnancy_is_ivf_or/", "score": 27}, {"question": "Asks for experiences and advice on surrogacy, both from parents who have used a gestational carrier and from surrogates themselves.", "answer": "Parents shared feeling relieved to have stress lifted off their shoulders and appreciating the support from the surrogate. Some parents experienced multiple losses and complications before turning to surrogacy. Surrogates shared finding carrying babies for others as a magical gift and may have personal connections and support from their own families during the process.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/1873kio/experiences_with_surrogacy/", "score": 18}, {"question": "Asks how to handle IVF decisions in the face of relationship issues and potential separation, specifically regarding custody of embryos.", "answer": "Consider checking any legal paperwork signed at the beginning of the process. Options include starting over with donor sperm, using the embryos and discussing co-parenting arrangements, or potentially being stopped from using the embryos. Have an honest conversation with your partner about involvement in parenting and co-parenting. Consider financial, physical, and emotional implications of each decision.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/n4vgi7/ivf_custody_battles_and_separation_those_who_have/", "score": 16}, {"question": "", "answer": "Asks for advice on dealing with repeated implantation failures and seeking success after multiple failed attempts with untested embryos.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/168yurk/advice_repeated_implantation_failure/", "score": 8}, {"question": "Asks about the logistics of gestational surrogacy, specifically regarding medical insurance, location proximity, and future contact with the surrogate.", "answer": "The process can vary, but generally, surrogates must meet specific medical and financial criteria. Surrogates may use their own insurance. Proximity and communication plans with the surrogate may depend on individual preferences and agreements.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/171eysy/positive_story_of_gestational_surrogacy/", "score": 157}, {"question": "Asks about legal agreements for frozen embryos, decision-making power regarding their use or disposal, and rights in cases of breakup or death.", "answer": "Clinics usually provide paperwork for couples to outline their wishes for embryos. State laws may influence options. Discussing and aligning on decisions with the partner beforehand is crucial.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/15krxmp/rights_to_embryos_down_the_line/", "score": 6}, {"question": "Asks if a haploid embryo can be retested after initially showing only one set of parent chromosomes.", "answer": "No comments provided in response to the question in the post.", "link": "/r/IVF/comments/13klgsr/retest_haploid_embryo/", "score": 1}]